# Girish Chandar G

Ann Arbor, Michigan

# **OBJECTIVE**

Enthusiastic graduate student interested in research roles in the domain of Computer Vision and Deep Learning. I have academic knowledge and research experience pertaining to Deep Learning applications in Computer Vision and proficient in Python and use of deep learning frameworks like PyTorch and Tensorflow.

#### **EDUCATION**

# University of Michigan, Ann Arbor, MI, USA

M.S. Electrical and Computer Engineering

Aug 2021 - Present

GPA - 4/4

# Indian Institute of Technology Gandhinagar, Gandhinagar, India

B.Tech. Electrical Engineering (minor Computer Science)

July 2016 - Aug 2020 GPA - 8.98/10

### COURSEWORK / SKILLS

- Foundations for Computer Vision (A)
- Matrix Methods for Machine Learning (A+)
- 3D Computer Vision
  - **MXNet** MATLAB, LabVIEW
- Numpy, OpenCV, Sklearn, Pandas

Machine Learning (A)

- Deep Learning for Computer Vision

• PyTorch, Tensorflow,

#### POSITION

Electee | Eta Kappa Nu (Honor Society)

Sep 2021 - Present

Research Assistant | Architecture and Artificial Intelligence Laboratory

Sep 2021 - Present

Research Intern | Zentron Labs

Oct 2020 - Aug 2021

# **INTERNSHIP**

# Auto Shape Detection in Machine Vision [2] | Zentron Labs | Python (Numpy, OpenCV)

Oct 2020 - Aug 2021

- Implemented Arc Detection algorithm that gives accuracies of 100% on simulated data and 80% on real data.
- Improved Line and Circle Detection accuracies from 65% to 90%

# Optimization based Inverse Rendering O University of Texas Dallas | PyTorch, MXNet, Numpy

May 2019 - July 2019

- Implemented algorithm for 3D face reconstruction from 2D images.
- 3D Morphable Model (3DMM) used as aprori mesh for efficient inverse rendering.

#### Microscopic Image Analysis O Clemson University | LabVIEW

May 2018 - July 2018

• Developed LabVIEW scripts for analyzing images from Magnetic Rotational Spectroscopy (MRS) experiment.

# PROJECTS

## Co-Tuning for Transfer Learning on TACO Dataset O | PyTorch

Dec 2021

- Implemented and verified the novel transfer algorithm proposed in "Co-tuning for Transfer Learning".
- First team to implement co-tuning on TACO (Trash Annotations in Context) dataset.

# Classification of Cancer Progression by Structuring Clinical Data | Tensorflow

Dec 2019

- Developed a novel model to predict the probability of cancer by structuring Electronic Health Records using NLP techniques.
- Explored MIMIC-III dataset extensively and verified its potential to be used for cancer prediction
- Structured the clinical data using CliNER, and BioBERT embedding

## Forensic Camera Model Classification using Local Binary Pattern | MATLAB

Apr 2018

- Implemented algorithm to identify source camera from images.
- Implemented One vs All classification model using Local Binary Patterns as features.
- Created novel dataset to test the model.

## Unsupervised Cross-Domain Image Transfer using GANO | PyTorch

Apr 2019

- Implemented Encoder+GAN with modified loss.
- Verified the results for cross-domain transfer between MNIST and SVHN.

# Acoustics 3-D Sound Source Localization | MATLAB

Apr 2019

- Participated in IEEE Signal Processing Cup (2019).
- Designed an 8-microphone array and created our own dataset to test the robustness of our algorithm.

# Patch based Multi-View Stereopsis | Python (Numpy, OpenCV)

Apr 2020

• Implemented an algorithm to get 3D scene data from multi-view stereo images.

#### Normalized cuts and segmentation () | Python (Numpy, OpenCV)

Apr 2019

Face Detection using Eigenfaces | Python (Numpy, OpenCV)

Dec 2018